Mss.Rec.30 Mss.Rec.30
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Song about a lady who lost a baby, 1954-08-05; 08-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:19; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska; Tazlina (Alaska)
  - Little Fish Song, 1954-08-05; 08-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:23; Billum, Mary Anne; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    Recorded at Tazlina Song Fest. Identification of the song, performer, and language is missing from the collector's documentation.
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tazlina (Alaska)
  - Unidentified song, 1954-08-05; 08-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:42; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - War Dance Song (?), 1954-08-05; 08-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:49; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    "Song begins in middle- Mentasta Pete drumming; Bacille George, Oscar Craig, Jim McKinley dance with paper 'feathers'.... Explanation by Oscar Craig. This is a Yukon song. Bacille George says they are broadcasting from Copper Center." Recorded at Tazlina Song Fest.
  - Up-the-Line Song and Dance, 1954-08-05; 08-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:31; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Recorded at Tazlina Song Fest.
  - Cooper River kIndjui Song, 1954-08-05; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:15; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Song explained by Jim McKinley as a kIndjui (Tlingit) dance song from Copper River. Recorded at Tazlina Song Fest.
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tazlina (Alaska); Tlingit Indians--Alaska--Music; Tlingit language
  - Tlingit Song, 1954-08-05; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:46; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - Tlingit Song and Dance, 1954-08-05; 09-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:05; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - Love Song, 1954-08-05; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:51; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    "Introduction by Oscar Craig. This is an old-fashioned love song, of the type composed and sung by a person of either sex who is worried about absent sweet-heart. The words mean: 'I want to see you.' 'You look good to me.' 'I see you standing and I would like to see you' - according to different informants. It was supposedly sung by Tenos Jack to Lotti Carlsen, and he was assisted by the entire group. No drum. Feet tap... Oscar Craig explains love-song. It is addressed to s'ude 'my cross-cousin' - who he calls 'second cousin.'" Recorded at Tazlina Song Fest.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Love songs; Tazlina (Alaska)
  - Ground Squirrel Song, 1954-08-05; 09-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - Timberwolf Song, 1954-08-05; 09-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:32; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    "FdeL asks for wolf song, used to call moose.... Oscar Craig explains that song is engi (taboo). Old-timers don't like to hear it. F thanks them - 'tcInan.' Craig says: 'Really tcInan.' According to informants at Chistochina this was a song, sung to make a peace after a war which the people don't like to recall." Recorded at Tazlina Song Fest.
    Ahtena Indians--History; Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tazlina (Alaska)
  - Northway Potlatch Song, 1954-08-05; 09-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Potlatch--Alaska; Tazlina (Alaska); Upper Tanana language
  - Tetlin or Tanacross Song, 1954-08-05; 09-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:53; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tanacross language; Tazlina (Alaska)
  - Tanana River Song, 1954-08-05; 09-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:42; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - Long Ago Song, 1954-08-05; 09-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:30; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - GoodTime Up-the-Line Song, 1954-08-05; 09-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:03; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Ahtena dance; Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tazlina (Alaska)
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1954-08-05; 09-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - Up-the-Line Song, 1954-08-05; 09-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:06; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - Wake Up and Come On song, 1954-08-05; 09-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:23; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
  - Frank Tanacross' Worry Song, 1954-08-05; 09-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:33; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    Song composed by the singer for his sister's funeral potlatch. Recorded at Tazlina Song Fest.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska; Tanacross language; Tazlina (Alaska)
  - Worry Song, 1954-08-05; 09-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:30; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    "Jim McKinley explains: 'Same thing again. Frank's boy died at Tanana River. His boy make it himself and he die.'" Recorded at Tazlina Song Fest.
  - Worry Song, 1954-08-05; 09-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:35; Billum, Mary Anne; Charley, Tenas; Craig, Oscar; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim; Pete, Mentasta
    "Jim McKinley explains; 'At Mentasta, 2-3 womens. Their father died one time and they make that song. All die.'" Recorded at Tazlina Song Fest.
  - Introduction by FdeL, 1954-08-20; 09-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:29; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Up-the-Line tcElali Whiskey Song, 1954-08-20; 09-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:41; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Drinking songs--Alaska; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Talk, 1954-08-20; 09-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:20; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Maggie; McClellan, Catharine
    "Lucy Albert speaks in Northway Athabaskan.... Frank Charley evidently paraphrases in Chistochina dialect.... Maggy Joe explains that Lucy Albert lost her cousin, the big chief, at Northway. She has just come back here to live near her two surviving relatives, - ?- and Frank Charley, her son." Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
    Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska; Upper Tanana language
  - Up-the-Line Dance Song, 1954-08-20; 09-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:51; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena dance; Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Long Lucy John's Drinking Song, 1954-08-20; 09-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:48; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tanacross language
  - Sorry Song for Frank Charley's Father, 1954-08-20; 09-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:05; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska
  - Tanacross Song, 1954-08-20; 09-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:04; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "This is a Tanacross song, belonging to Big Frank, a wUdjicyu man, now dead. It is a sorry song. Some one else said it was a dance song." Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
  - Northway Christmas Tree Song, 1954-08-20; 09-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:54; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Upper Tanana language
  - Tanacross Song for Christmas Day and New Year's Day, 1954-08-20; 09-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:19; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
  - Santa Claus Song, 1954-08-20; 09-27; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:02; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
  - SaRani gai (Crow) & nAlbei (Seagull) Song, 1954-08-20; 09-28; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "[Song] is said to be about Crow and Seagull who ate too much at a potlatch." Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Dance Song from Tanacross, 1954-08-20; 09-29; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:12; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tanacross language
  - Up-the-Line Dance Song, 1954-08-20; 09-30; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:22; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "Ralf Sanford: 'Another one from Tanacross.' Harry Frank: 'From Nabesna River.' Others mention Northway, Tanacross, Tatlin." Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
    Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tanacross language
  - Adam Sanford's Drinking Song, 1954-08-20; 09-31; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:09; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Adam; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    A song composed in imitation of a drunken man trying to use big words. The song is introduced by the singer in English and "Athabaskan"--most likely Southern Tutchone. Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
  - Northway "Muskrat" Drinking Song, 1954-08-20; 09-32; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:31; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "Bill Joe introduces the song. It was composed by Titus John, former husband of Lucy (Albert??). 'When I'm drunk I act like a muskrat, go around collecting grass.' There is also said to be a reference to an outboard motor on a lake." Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Drinking songs--Alaska; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Muskrat
  - Sorry Song for Mrs. Banzanita Billy's Boy, 1954-08-20; 09-33; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:34; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "Introduction by Bill Joe. The father or mother made this song after the death of the son, while listening to a phonograph record." Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
  - Tanacross Dance Song, 1954-08-20; 09-34; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:36; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "Kate Sanford introduces song. 'No sing at Chistochina. Not many people this place.'" Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
  - Introduction by FdeL, 1954-08-22; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:35; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
  - Song from Knik, or Cantwell, or Eklutna, Knik Arm, Cook Inlet, 1954-08-22; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:36; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Dena'ina language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Tanana Crossing Song, 1954-08-22; 10-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:58; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
  - Tanacross Song, 1954-08-22; 10-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:22; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Bill Joe introduces Tanana Crossing song. Bill Joe and Jim Sinyone drum. Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
  - Tanana River Song, 1954-08-22; 10-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:01; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Bill Joe and Jim Sinyone drumming. Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
  - Tanacross Song, 1954-08-22; 10-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:55; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
  - Dawson Hanging Song, 1954-08-22; 10-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:07; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Song explained by Frank Charley: "In Dawson, 1903, a woman had three sons. They were hanging them for murder. The last boy said 'Goodby world, and goodby Mother,' when he go to hanging." Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Chistochina (Alaska); Han language; Hangings--Yukon--Dawson; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Tanacross Song, 1954-08-22; 10-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:12; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
  - Tanana River Song, 1954-08-22; 10-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:41; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
  - Frank Charley's Sorry Song for his Brother, 1954-08-22; 10-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:03; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "Translation by Bill Joe. The song was composed by Frank Charley for his brother who died up Suslotna River. It was sung at a potlatch for him. It makes Frank feel good when he sing that song." Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
  - Jim Sinyone's Sorry Song for his Father's Brother, 1954-08-22; 10-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:56; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "Jim Sinyone introduces the song. His is from Gulkana. The song is for his father's brother, Suslotna Charley, who died in 1942." Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
  - Maggy Joe's Song for Oscar Isaac, 1954-08-22; 10-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
  - Love Song to Dick Ewan, by Maggy Joe & Kate Sanford, 1954-08-22; 10-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "The song was composed that afternoon, on a trip to Gulkana. Dick Ewan is the cross-cousin, sudE', of the two sisters." Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Love songs
  - Tanacross Dance Song, 1954-08-22; 10-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:23; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Dance; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Shaman's Money Song, 1954-08-22; 10-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:11; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "The song was composed by a wudjicyu gyEnin, shaman, who knew how to make money come down from above. He sold it to his gya'znE' (apposite), the nAltsina chief of Gulkana for lots of cloth, a muzzle-loader, and dentalia. Then the original composed could no longer sing it.... 'Dance too much...Stand up and singing' are spoken in Tanacross language after the song." Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tanacross language
  - Tanacross Dance Song, 1954-08-22; 10-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:13; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Song was composed in 1916. Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.
  - Tanacross Dance Song, 1954-08-22; 10-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:08; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
  - Northway Gospel Hymn "Let it Shine", 1954-08-22; 10-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:41; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Religion; Upper Tanana language
  - Gospel Hymn "Nothing but the Blood of Jesus", 1954-08-22; 10-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:54; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest. Tape ends in middle of song.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Chistochina (Alaska); Hymns; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Religion
  - Rabbit Song, 1954-08-22; 10-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:02; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
  - Goodby Song, 1954-08-22; 10-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:16; Albert, Lucy; Charley, Frank; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Frank, Harry; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
    "The words mean; 'Goodby, sudE', I follow you' or `Etsuda nANgAl st'Al 'I like to follow my sweetheart.'" Recorded at Chistochina Song Fest.